MOHAMMAD WAHID

WIOHAWIWIAD WAIH

+8801948780674

(0)

mohammadwahid.eng@gmail.com



 $-\Box$

- П

http://mohammadwahid.com

PROFILE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

A software engineer with over 9 years of experience in web design & development. Skilled in developing web applications, rest API and automation engineering. I try to prove myself as a quick learner and high-energetic person to face any challenge, and to build up my career in such organizations in any sector where the contribution will be acknowledged.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

RootNext Solutions, 2021 - Present

- E2E automation and performance testing.
- Web application development using Laravel.
- Making application using NodeJS, React, Vue, HTML, CSS etc.
- WordPress theme customization.
- GitHub version controlling with CI/CD.

WEB DESIGNER & DEVELOPER

Bento Agency, 2018 - 2022

- Design and develop mobile friendly, multilingual, cross browser supported WordPress websites from scratch.
- API integration and documentation in premium WordPress newsletter plugin named Newsletter Glue.

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Upwork Inc., 2013 - 2021

- Worked as an individual freelancer.
- Worked both in frontend and backend.
- Completed more than 200 different projects.
- Tracked over 1100 working hours.

EDUCATION

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (B.Sc.)

Bangladesh University of Business & Technology (BUBT), 2016 - 2020

I completed my graduation in computer science and engineering (CSE) and obtained CGPA 3.97 out of 4. I participated in many intra university programming contests. I created 4 different software development projects during my university life.

HIGHER SECONDARY CERTIFICATE (H.S.C.)

Govt. Mohammadpur Model School & College, 2011 - 2013

I passed my higher secondary certificate (HSC) examination from the science group and obtained GPA 4.40 out of 5.

PRO SKILLS

HTML/CSS	
JavaScript	
Rest API	
Cypress, Jest	
React, Vue	
WordPress	
GitHub	
Postman, k6	
Photoshop	

PERSONAL SKILLS

Creativity	
Team Work	
Hard Work	
Leadership	

REFERENCE

LESLEY SIM

Strategy Director, Bento Agency
Email: lesley@bento.agency

DR. MUHAMMAD FIROZ MRIDHA

Associate Professor (CSE), BUBT

Phone: +8801674791594